[{"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "At Company ABC we like to promote from within, whenever possible. Where would you like to see your career grow over the next 3-5 years?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about the ways that you would like to see your career flourish. What can Company ABC offer you that you are not receiving with your current employer? Show your enthusiasm for career growth with Company ABC.", "\"I am currently working in a smaller organization where promotions and growth are limited. I am interested in joining Company ABC as a sales representative and then plan to grow my way into a leadership role. In 3-5 years I would love to be in a dedicated leadership position such as a regional manager or customer care manager.\"", "\"Ideally, five years from now, I would love to see myself growing into a more prominent leadership role within your organization. My career interests align very nicely with your company's goals which helps me to see a great long-term fit here.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "Do you personally own any of our product? What is your favourite product from Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you are personally acquainted with any of their product. Talk to the hiring manager about any personal exposure you may have to their product. Be sure to reinforce your experience positively! \n\nIf you have not personally owned any of the Company ABC product, talk about an item you have your eye on and why you hope to own it one day.", "\"Yes, I have been lucky enough to purchase A, B, and C from Company ABC! The craftsmanship is undeniable, and I feel proud to have purchased those items for myself. One can never have too much luxury in their life!\"", "\"I have not personally owned any of the product from Company ABC; however I have admired it for many years. Product XYZ is on my bucket list for personal purchases because the craftsmanship is undeniable.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "Why do you want a career with Company ABC?", "answers": ["You may be taking the next step in your career or starting fresh out of college. It's important to do your research on Company ABC before interviewing. You can start by browsing the 'About Us' page on their website to learn about their mission and what they are doing to give back to the community, for example. Perhaps they started their company 50 years ago, so they know what they're doing! Share a few facts you learned from your research and explain how working there will help you accomplish your goals.", "\"I am newer to my career and feel that Company ABC will offer me the training that I need to kick-start my sales career. I have had my eye on your company for a year now and am confident that I will find a long-term fit here with all of the growth opportunities, training, and other methods of support that you offer.\"", "\"I have been passively seeking a new position for quite some time and haven't jumped on anything yet because I want to make sure it's the right fit. I feel that this job is right for me, at this point in my career, because it offers an opportunity for me to utilize my recent education in business management while giving me an opportunity to advance in luxury sales.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "At Company ABC we prefer to hire those dedicated to their professional growth. How do you plan to grow your career this year?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are dedicated to your professional growth and that you can see yourself quickly advancing with Company ABC. Give an example of how you maintain a dedication to your growth and advancement in the workplace.", "\"I am very career focused and would like to see my career grow into a management focused role. I have been reading books on leadership this year which is helping me to prepare for the responsibility when the opportunity comes my way.\"", "\"I agree that professional growth is significant for any person wanting to advance in their career. I plan to grow my career by fully immersing myself in training at Company ABC and taking full advantage of any additional workshops and courses that come my way.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "Collaboration is important to us at Company ABC. How do you motivate your fellow team members?", "answers": ["You don't have to be a manager or a team leader to motivate others. Offering a listening ear or providing words of encouragement can make a world of difference to your coworkers. Sometimes, just being a positive influence and showing up consistently can also make a difference. \n\nIf you have worked in a leadership role, think of ways you helped set clear goals or helped individuals cultivate a new skill. Reflect on your experience and share some ways that you have helped encourage others to keep up the good work!", "\"I motivate my fellow team members by coming to work with an exceptional attitude every day. I won't allow anyone's bad mood to let me down. That influence alone has helped many of my coworkers get through their day on a more positive note.\"", "\"I believe that I motivate solely through my actions and my positive disposition. I try always to have a smile on my face and be ready for the next challenge. It's a contagious disposition!\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "Tell me about a time at work when your integrity was challenged. How did you handle it?", "answers": ["Have you ever faced a time, in the workplace, where you were put to the test when it came to your integrity? Perhaps a co-worker has asked you to lie, or you were tempted to be dishonest on your time sheet when the boss was away. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you overcame the temptation to be dishonest.", "\"Last year our manager went away on vacation for three weeks. Some of my co-workers wanted to falsify our time sheets to reflect overtime hours that we did not work. I disagreed and was able to convince them that it was a bad idea and certainly not worth being fired over.\"", "\"I once had a subordinate that would perform work after clocking out. There was a rumor later that I forced my team to work off the clock to save the company money. I did not know it was happening, and I certainly did not ask anyone to work outside of their scheduled shift. The situation was cleared up later.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "At Company ABC we have had concerns with employee theft. What would you do if you caught a co-worker stealing?", "answers": ["Some businesses have trouble with employee theft, and they need to make sure that they are hiring someone who is honest and trustworthy. Talk to the interviewer about the steps you would take if you caught a co-worker stealing at Company ABC. Take this as an opportunity to reiterate your loyalty.", "\"I am sure that you have an internal policy for employee theft so I can assure you that I would follow the required steps to report the theft. I am a trustworthy person with a strong track record of honesty with my previous employers.\"", "\"If I caught an employee stealing, I would report the incident immediately. As a previous manager, I understand the value of employee honesty.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "At Company ABC we pride ourselves in our high end products. Walk me through your experience in selling high end products.", "answers": ["Company ABC products are in the multi-thousand dollar price tag arena. Assure the interviewer that you are able, and comfortable, in selling products with a more significant price tag. Use examples from your work history and talk about a massive sale or large sales target from the past.", "\"I started my career in luxury sales with company ABC and, after spending two years there, I moved on to company XYZ which was an even higher price tag. With ABC, my average sale was $2500, and with XYZ, it was $6500. I am accustomed to sales quotas of $1M plus and would have no issue asking for the sale when it comes to a $10,000 luxury handbag or fine couture item.\"", "\"I have a total of 5 years' experience in luxury sales. This experience has included designer labels, diamonds, and cars. I am most comfortable working in a luxury setting and would fit in very well here at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "In your opinion, what is the biggest difference when it comes to selling low end and high end products?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you understand the approach required to sell Company ABC products successfully. Compare the sales of lower end products to luxury products and discuss what you feel is the most significant difference when it comes to closing the deal.", "\"In my opinion, the most significant difference in selling high-end products is that you must have incredible product knowledge. You need to show value and display why your product is superior, and also why the luxury is worth the price tag. With Company ABC, the brand story is exceptional and the fact that you have been around for so many years is incredible.\"", "\"The sales system needs to be more precise, and the sales process may be slower when it comes to selling high-end products. One must give exceptional service, no matter what the price range is of the sale; however.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "Do you have any formal sales training or certifications?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about any sales training you have attended, either independently or through a previous employer. Be sure to highlight any of your biggest 'take-away's' from these courses. If you do not have any formal sales training be sure to express your willingness to attend any training encouraged by Company ABC.", "\"I do not have any formal sales training - simply, on-the-job training in all of my current positions. I would be very interested in expanding my sales knowledge. Are there specific sales training programs that you recommend I take?\"", "\"I have attended a variety of sales courses through Dale Carnegie and Sandler Sales. My biggest takeaway from these courses were the lessons on building my business through referrals.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "What is the most expensive product or service you have ever sold?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you are capable and experienced when it comes to selling high-end goods. Talk about your best sale, biggest win, or a significant career highlight that excites you. Now is the time to brag about yourself a little bit!", "\"I have sold luxury products for many years, but I would say that the most expensive was a vehicle worth nearly $400K when working at the Aston Martin dealership. That was an incredible day for me!\"", "\"The most expensive product I have ever sold was a $40,000 engagement ring. It was so exhilarating to close a sale that big and it made me thirsty for more big career wins like that!\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "At Company ABC we always seek to hire top performers. Tell me about your past 3 years' sales targets and results.", "answers": ["Walk the interviewer through your sales targets and results, being sure to highlight your top achievements. If you have fallen short of your expected targets, you need to own up to that and discuss the situation. Honesty is always the best policy. If you have documentation to back up your sales, bring that with you.", "\"My past three years' sales targets have been $700K, $850K and $1.2M consecutively. Year 1, I met my target at $720K, Year 2 I exceeded by 21% and this past year I was shy just $60K. I attribute this to a substantial return that I ended up having to take due to a manufacturer's defect. Also, the economy has been a bit lighter than we expected this year, and luxury goods did take a bit of a hit.\"", "\"I have exceeded my sales targets for the last five years, in fact! I attribute my success to the great client follow up process that I have, as well as my high customer referral rating. In my current role, my annual target is $500,000. The last 3 years I have sold $520,000, $589,000 and $610,000. I have seen consistent growth and this year am aiming to reach $670,000.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "At Company ABC we always take our appearance and professionalism seriously. How do you feel about adhering to a code of ethics including rules surrounding your workplace wardrobe?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about any previous positions where you have been asked to follow a code of ethics, and had to adhere to a particular dress code. Keep your answer positive and assure the interviewer that you are willing to support their specific codes of conduct.", "\"I have adhered to a dress code the past three years. I like it because it takes the guesswork out of my day but also because it gives the organization a professional and clean look. I am happy to adhere to any code of ethics put forth by Company ABC.\"", "\"I would love to see your code of ethics and workplace wardrobe documents before fully agreeing; however, I am in full understanding of the importance when it comes to presenting a united front in the workplace as well as appropriate dress.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "We have peak seasons in the fine retailer industry such as Christmas and Valentines Day. Are you able to work overtime, weekends, and evenings during those times?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you can provide flexibility in your schedule when it comes to the needs of the company. If you have any restrictions on your calendar, this is an excellent time to address them. If you do have limitations, be sure to offer a feasible workaround!", "\"I am more than willing to be a flexible employee for Company ABC. Currently, I do not have many restrictions on my availability, except for Tuesday evenings. If that is a concern, I can always try to work around that engagement.\"", "\"At this point, my schedule is wide open, and I welcome the idea of overtime work!\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "Working for a fine retailer is often much like owning your own business. How have you shown initiative in building your business, or client base, in the past?", "answers": ["Many fine retailers require their sales staff to build a portfolio of clients and create repeat business, resulting in substantial commission opportunities. Share with the interviewer how you develop your 'business' and ensure that your targets are consistently met. Do you have a strong portfolio of clients that follow you from one position to another? This client base is especially important in a luxury retail environment.", "\"In my current role I have built a strong portfolio of clients who I call whenever new products come in. It's the basis of my business and my clients provide me with a firm referral basis as well. I went from a client base of zero to, now, over 150 repeat buyers who come specifically to the store to see me when they want to check out a new collection or refresh their wardrobe.\"", "\"I am a true entrepreneur at heart and have been a small business owner in the past. It was an e-commerce store related to beauty and lifestyle products. I enjoyed the opportunity to work on a start-up and learn about social media marketing. I successfully sold my half of the company to my business partner last year.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "At Company ABC we are looking for team members who will treat every customer like they are the most important customer in the world. Tell me about your customer service skills and how you will uphold this value, if hired.", "answers": ["Customer service is a top priority for Company ABC so be sure to display to the interviewer that you are confident in your customer service skills. If you have an example of a time when you went over and above the call of duty, this is a great time to talk about that.", "\"I am consistently the most recognized sales professional in my current organization when it comes to positive customer feedback. I have very strong follow up skills and always ensure my customers have my undivided attention. I look forward to bringing my strong customer service skills to Company ABC.\"", "Here are a few keywords you can  use to describe your customer service skills: \n\n- Honest\n- Friendly \n- Helpful \n- Patient\n- Attentive \n- Clear Communicator\n- Use of Positive Language \n- Strong Product Knowledge \n- Goal Oriented"]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "At Company ABC we keep a close eye on product performance and sales. Are you accustomed to positions where you are responsible for a particular sales target each week?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about how your performance has been measured in the past. Are you comfortable with being monitored on a daily, weekly, and monthly basis? Highlight some of your sales goals from the past, and discuss how you met or exceeded those goals.", "\"I am accustomed to being closely monitored when it comes to my personal KPI's and performance. I am open to coaching and motivation to keep my performance at its highest level. Currently, I am measured on my daily, weekly and monthly performance. It keeps me accountable, and I enjoy the challenge. For the past three years, I have been in the top 10 for sales earnings, company-wide. I plan to continue that success here at Company ABC.\"", "\"In my current position, I am not responsible for a specific sales target. I do keep an eye on my sales on my own because I like how it motivates me.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "Tell me something about yourself that I wouldn't know from reading your resume.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to get to know you apart from what is on your resume. You are indeed not obligated to discuss personal matters such as your kids, or relationship status, for instance. Stick with a couple of fun facts to show the interviewer that you are a real person, too. Your answer should be unique so that you are a memorable candidate!  \n\nFocus on unique non-work related skills or hobbies.  For example, you might share that you enjoy beat-boxing or making origami swans. Be prepared for the interviewer to stop you and ask you to perform your skill on the spot when its possible! (This will make you unforgettable!)", "\"I am an avid marathon runner and have traveled to 10 countries in the last eight years to compete in a variety of races. I am a competitive individual and enjoy keeping fit.\"", "\"A bit about me - I love to travel, read, and conduct research. I am a recent grad from Columbia University and have spent the past 12 months traveling the world. It was the best experience that I could have given myself as I was able to learn so much from seeing how the rest of the world lives. I returned to the US just last month and have been actively looking for work the past couple of weeks. I am looking forward to getting into the routine of a career again.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "How do you think we can be more innovative at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer isn't asking you to try to reinvent the wheel, right on the spot! You can share an idea for an upcoming trend or talk about a new way they can give back to communities in need. This is a smart way for Company ABC to test your knowledge of their organization as well. \n\nPick a topic like investing in employees, or developing a phone app. Take into account their values so that you can share an idea that they would find exciting and relevant.", "\"I know from my research that Company ABC puts a lot of effort into gaining momentum from millennial customers. This demographic is highly technical and constantly in touch via social media outlets. I would consider creating more consistent hashtags and additional hashtag-driven contests for social media. The customer could take photo's with your product, and they would post it on their social media accounts. You can never have too much exposure to places like Facebook, Instagram, and Snapchat.\"", "\"It's difficult for me to provide feedback on innovation without having worked here; although, there is always room for improvement, in any organization. I find your branding to be very clean and energetic. One suggestion I would make would be to advertise more on less traditional platforms such as Spotify or social media.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "When have you had to adapt to change?", "answers": ["Being able to adapt to change in the workplace is an essential skill to possess. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have had to adjust to changes on the job. How did you handle the transition? Was it a positive reaction?", "\"In my current role there is a lot of turnover when it comes to our management team. I have had to adapt to 3 new managers in the past four years. It is not the ideal situation, but I can adjust for the good of the team.\"", "\"Last year our company was sold to a competitor and a lot our policies and procedures changed, along with some senior management. I did adapt well throughout the changes because I fully believed in the company's vision.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "What would you do if a client asked you about a product or service and you were unsure of the answer?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know if you are an independent thinker. Explain that you would take the time to try and figure out the answer, but you are not afraid to ask questions if you need to.", "\"If I had a client ask me about something that I didn't know enough about, I would find the answer for them before giving a potentially false answer. I am okay with admitting when I don't know something, and I love to learn new things. Of course, I would find the answer quickly by asking the appropriate person or finding it within the company's internal resources.\"", "\"I plan to know everything possible about your products so I sure hope this would not happen to me very often! Should it happen, I would utilize all of the resources available to me or ask a manager for assistance.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "Do you feel performance should be rewarded over experience?", "answers": ["Do you feel that you should be paid based on tenure, results, or both? Discuss this with the interviewer and back your answer with an example, if possible.", "\"I feel that employees should be paid, and rewarded, based on their performance. A new employee would be greatly motivated through being rewarded for performance and it I believe this model encourages a healthy competition with tenured employees.\"", "\"I feel both performance and experience should be equally rewarded and weighted.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "At Company ABC, we like to reward our best employees. How do you feel about performance incentives?", "answers": ["Performance incentives can be very motivating, and Company ABC knows it! Talk to the interviewer about your feelings on performance incentives. Keep in mind, most employees who do not love performance incentives usually have a history of under-performing!", "\"I feel that performance incentives are a great idea. They keep an employee motivated to do a great job and ensure that they are on top of their KPI's. The majority of people are very enthused about being rewarded for their successes. I know I am!\"", "\"I think performance incentives are important for driving people to get results.  For me, they give me some skin in the game and get my team engaged in making an impact towards the results.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "Tell me about your experience in training and coaching others.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to see that you are capable of leading and training others, even if you are not in an official leadership role. Discuss a time when you have taken on coaching responsibilities. If you do not bring experience coaching in the workplace, perhaps you can discuss any coaching experience you may have when it comes to extracurricular such as sports teams or volunteer work.", "\"In my last position, I trained new hires on how to use our CRM system. It was a very cool experience because it showed me that I love to teach and train. I am good at explaining how things work. It required a lot of patience, but it helped me to recognize my leadership potential.\"", "If you lack experience in training and coaching, you can respond with: \"I haven't had the opportunity to coach or train anyone in the workplace formally, but I am interested in learning how to be an effective leader. I am eager to learn how to motivate others best.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "Would you consider yourself a creative person?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about any interest that you have in creativity and how you have implemented that desire in the workplace. Even if you do not consider yourself to be a 'creative person,' there is a substantial change that you have made creative minded decisions in your career.", "\"I do consider myself to be a creative individual. One example of this would be the telephone sales scripts that I crafted for our inside sales team. They were lively and effective, and sales increased by 23% in the first 90 days of implementation.\"", "\"I am someone who alternates back and forth with the right/left brain, but I will always consider myself a very creative person.  I admire the creativity and unconventional thinking in business and arts.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "At Company ABC we like to keep our employees motivated on the job. What causes you to feel dissatisfied in your job?", "answers": ["Everyone will have their particular triggers that cause them to feel dissatisfaction on the job. Talk to the interviewer about any factors that may deflate or discourage you in the workplace. Help Company ABC to understand how they can motivate you!", "\"I can feel dissatisfaction on the job when I am not feeling heard or when there is not mutual respect among the team members. I work best in more harmonious situations where there is little drama or gossip.\"", "\"I do not like to dwell on the negative so I would much prefer to discuss what makes me feel most motivated on the job! I am very motivated by surroundings where I feel listened to, valued, and respected.  A positive mindset and environment are important to me.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "What kind of people do you enjoy working with?", "answers": ["Culture fit is a crucial factor when looking for a new position. Talk to the interviewer about the types of personalities that you best work with. Be sure to remain positive and avoid using this as an opportunity to speak poorly of previous colleagues.", "\"I best enjoy working with individuals who are driven, positive, energetic, and take accountability for their work. I do have the ability to work with a large variety of individuals; however, these are the ideal traits I would see in future colleagues.\"", "\"Positive and driven people are the type that I love working with most! With that said, I can get along well with an extensive range of individuals.\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "I have worked with Company ABC for 12 years now. What questions do you have for me?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to have questions ready for the interviewer. Review the Company ABC website and other online resources to ensure the questions you are asking are not mundane, or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a list of items you could have found the answers to from merely watching a video on their company site! \n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What is your favorite part about working here? \n- What is the company's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the most significant change in the luxury fashion industry over the past three years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"Thank you for asking - I do have a few questions. What is top of mind when it comes to filling this role? In addition, what types of career growth opportunities would follow this position? And lastly, do you have internal candidates who are also interviewing for this position?\""]}, {"topic": "Fine+Retailer", "question": "Are you applying for any other jobs?", "answers": ["It always puts a little bit of fire under the hiring manager if they are aware that you are actively looking for a new position. Tell the interviewer about your search so far. Be honest and give a legitimate timeline on when you expect to be accepting an offer.", "\"I am keeping an eye out for viable positions. Although I am not in final stages with any other company, I am actively seeking a new position.\"", "\"I am passively seeking a new opportunity which means that I am very particular about where I apply. At this point, I have interviewed with a couple of companies; however, they were not the right roles for me. I am very excited to learn more about this position with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "Tell me about an error or mistake you made because of a breakdown in communication from you or one of your team members.", "answers": ["On occasion, mistakes will happen, and communication will be broken. Talk to the interviewer about a time that this occurred in the workplace. How did you resolve the situation?", "\"I recall one instance where I misread an email from one of my subordinates. The punctuation was incorrect, and I read it in in a dire tone rather than in a positive one, as it was intended. After a tense conversation, the employee clarified her intention, and it seems I was mistaken. She and I agreed to exercise verbal communication on a regular basis to avoid a similar situation from happening again.\"", "\"We recently had a missing link in communications to one of our vendors, who we signed on to provide a large service.  They were not aware of a change in the agreement which cost the company wasted time, resources and money.  We were able to identify the breakdown in communication and change the process to ensure it does not happen again.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "We are in a very competitive market. Why do you want to work for Company ABC?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer the reasons why working for Company ABC would be a top choice for you vs. their competitors. Personalize your answer by utilizing the research you have conducted on their organization.", "\"I do understand that your industry is very competitive; however, I feel that you stand out from the crowd. I want to work for your company because you are a long-standing employer with a strong reputation for quality products and friendly service.\"", "\"I chose to apply to your organization because I have a few friends who work for you and they have amazing things to say. Reputation is everything, and your industry reputation seems great.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "Do you have reliable transportation?", "answers": ["Even if you're not expected to drive for the job, you will need to have some form of reliable transportation. If you take the bus or ride a bike that works too! Simply share that you have the means to get you to work consistently on time.", "\"I have reliable transportation. My vehicle is well maintained, and I am comfortable with the amount of travel required to get to here every day.\"", "\"I take public transit; however, I find it to be very reliable. I was late to work only once last year, and that was due to a snowstorm which stalled all of our employee's commute - including those with personal vehicles. Rest assured, I am reliable and will always come to work on time.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "Are you looking for a long term employment opportunity?", "answers": ["Company ABC believes in investing in their employees, and they want to know that you will return the favor by offering a longer-term commitment. Be sure to let the interviewer know that you are not just using this opportunity as a temporary stepping-stone. \n\nIf you are looking for long-term employment: \"You can see on my resume that I have strong tenure in my previous positions. I would like to find a long-term fit where I can grow into a management or leadership type of role.\"", "\"You can see on my resume that I have strong tenure in my previous positions. I would like to find a long-term fit where I can grow into a management or leadership type of role.\"", "If you are looking for a shorter term solution: \"I am looking for a temporary position for the summer. My goal is to earn additional money for University this Fall. I am willing to work overtime, weekends, and holidays to make my financial goals happen.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "In this role with Company ABC there are a few levels of management. Tell me about your ability to accept guidance and feedback from multiple managers.", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are accustomed to working with multiple department managers at a time. Give an example of a time where you have worked with cross-functional management teams.", "\"In my last position I worked in the stocking department and was required to answer to the deli, bakery, and fresh produce managers. I am accustomed to working with multiple managers. This experience has helped me to learn more about how important clear communication is.\"", "\"I have no issue when it comes to accepting feedback from multiple supervisors or managers. I truly believe that we can all learn so much from each-other. I always appreciate constructive feedback when it's coming from a good place.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "Do you have any experience in up-selling?", "answers": ["Company ABC is all about excellent customer service as well as excellent value and product. If hired, how do you plan to up-sell your customers on new and exciting products? Assure the interviewer that you are a natural salesperson.", "\"Up-selling is everywhere in the grocery world. From cashier displays to in-store demonstrations, to BOGO sales - there is always an option for the customer to spend more money during each visit. I do have experience in sales and fully understand the importance of up-selling in the grocery environment. I may ask the customer if they want the '3 for the price of 2' deal or if they want 10% off their next grocery purchase if they buy over $100 in groceries today. I always have my eye open for new up-selling opportunities.\"", "\"Yes, I do have experience in up-selling. In my current position, as a cashier, I will remind customers of any sale that we have going on. I'll casually say something like, 'Did you know that our cereals are three for the price of two? Would you like me to have another two boxes bagged for you?' It's surprising to me how many people do not take advantage of these great deals, so it feels good to help them save money while pushing the store's promotions at the same time.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "What work situations excite and motivate you?", "answers": ["It is essential, for your success, that the hiring manager knows how to keep you motivated and excited to come to work every day. Share with the interviewer what they could do to ensure that you are happy and productive.", "\"I am most motivated, on the job, when tasks are organized, and the vibe is positive. I value strong teamwork and good leadership.\"", "\"It does not take a lot to keep me motivated. If I work in a positive environment with a forward-thinking team, I am a very happy employee. If you see me going above and beyond, a quick thanks or small recognition of my hard work is good enough for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "Describe your working relationship with your previous or current colleagues.", "answers": ["When you answer this question be sure to remain positive, even if the experience wasn't. Avoid talking about any previous drama and do not speak poorly of your colleagues. \n\nIf you had a good relationship with your previous colleagues: \"I get along well with most personalities. My colleagues were great team players, and we would often meet up after work for drinks or team activities.\" \n\nIf you did not have a good relationship with your previous colleagues: \"I have had better relationships in the past, but we did the best that we could. Our communication styles were all very different which made it challenging at times.\"", "\"I get along well with most personalities. My colleagues were great team players, and we would often meet up after work for drinks or team activities.\"", "\"All of the colleagues I have worked with have shared a very respectful relationship with me. We have shared goals, and we share knowledge to accomplish those things to the best we can.  Each of us has a part in the company's success, and we utilize communication to make it happen.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "Our stores are open nearly 24/7. Are you able to accommodate early start times, late start times, split shifts, weekends, overtime hours, and holidays?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if there are restrictions on your availability. If your schedule is wide open, that is great - but, most people do have some conflicts in their schedule. Discuss your availability openly with the hiring manager.", "\"My schedule is quite flexible except for Sunday mornings. I am eager to work as many hours as possible and will certainly be available to work overtime as needed.\"", "\"My school schedule requires me to work a typical 8-4 Monday to Friday and my weekend availability is completely open.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "What type of career growth do you feel we can offer you here at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you see this opportunity as a long-term fit. Talk to the hiring manager about the career growth that you are hoping for. How does the position with Company ABC fit in with your goals?", "\"I am looking forward to growing into a leadership and management position. Because you offer internal training and you promote from within, I am confident that Company ABC could offer me the career growth that I am seeking.\"", "\"I hope to see steady career growth as I earn it, and as I feel ready to take on additional responsibilities. I would be happy to work my way into a cashier position once I have proven my capabilities at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "Give me an example of a time when you went above and beyond.", "answers": ["Display to the interviewer that you can do more than the bare minimum. Show that you can react appropriately when you see that your employer has a need that goes beyond your usual day-to-day expectations.", "\"Last week I noticed that my manager had not completed the schedule for the following week. Some of the staff were complaining that they didn't have their work schedule yet. Rather than going to my manager with the complaint, I offered to take on some of her workload so that she would have the time to complete the schedule. We worked together for a couple of overtime hours that day and were able to catch her up on everything. It felt good to help but also benefited me by way of organization.\"", "\"I often go above and beyond what is expected of me. Most recently, I agreed to cover for a co-worker who was on short-term medical leave. I worked 10 hour days for two weeks so that our productivity did not suffer.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "This position requires you to lift boxes up to 50 pounds. Are you physically capable of this task?", "answers": ["Many jobs require some intermediate to heavy lifting. At Company ABC there will be new stock coming in all the time; some light and some heavy. Assure the interviewer that you are physically capable of assisting with the receiving of stock. If you do have limitations, this is the time to disclose them. You do not need to get overly personal with health issues, but you do need to be upfront and honest. Focus on what you CAN do versus what you cannot.", "\"I can lift up to 50 pounds and do not have any physical restrictions. I am fit, injury free, and ready to work!\"", "\"I can bend and lift; however, 50 pounds may be more than I can handle at this time. With that said, I can certainly lift boxes up to 25 pounds.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "What do you know about Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you are engaged in the interview process and that you have researched Company ABC before attending your interview. Discuss a couple of the positive points you have come across and be sure to compliment the organization on a recent award or achievement.", "\"I have researched your company online and see that you have been around for over 50 years, first starting out as a family owned and operated local grocer. Your work environment seems very friendly, your stores are clean, and I am happy to see that you always offer low prices on quality items, even local and organic produce!\"", "\"I have researched your company online and like what I see so far. I know that you are very focused on your customers while still keeping a great investment in your employees. Your workplace culture seems open and communicative which is what I am looking for.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "At Company ABC we take our theft prevention programs very seriously. Have you ever caught a coworker stealing? What did you do?", "answers": ["Company ABC has multiple locations and tons of employees. Of course, employee theft would be a concern when your company is so large. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have faced dishonesty in the workplace. Show that you are capable of handling a situation like this with integrity and professionalism.", "\"I completely empathize with companies that struggle with theft prevention. My parents are small business owners, and I understand the efforts that go into theft prevention programs. If I were to catch a co-worker stealing, I would report the situation immediately. There should be zero tolerance for theft and dishonesty in the workplace.\"", "\"Fortunately, I have never been a situation where I caught a co-worker stealing. If I caught an employee stealing, I would report the incident immediately. As a previous manager, I understand the value of employee honesty.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "How do you handle dissatisfied customers?", "answers": ["You will come across dissatisfied customers from time to time - no matter how hard you try to please. You can't please everyone! Talk to the interviewer about your ability to handle dissatisfied customers.", "\"I have had my fair share of dissatisfied customers and am not shy when it comes to dispute resolution. I find that listening to customers is almost always enough when it comes to diffusing a situation. They want to be heard and feel acknowledged.\"", "\"It's never fun to have a dissatisfied customer as I truly care that everyone is happy after my interactions with them. If I have a customer who is unhappy, I will ask them what I can do, or could have done, differently. I will actively listen and then change my actions to create a satisfactory result.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "We have very busy and productive work days at Company ABC. How do you handle a larger than average workload?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to be assured that you can handle the workload required of you in this position and that you will not become overwhelmed if/when workloads unexpectedly increase. When workloads increase, stress levels do too. How do you react?", "\"When I have a large workload on my plate, I do not stress over the tasks that are in front of me. Rather, I make a simple plan of which tasks are a high priority and which tasks are a lower priority. The higher priority tasks, I complete first. Through this system, I can focus on my tasks individually, rather than stress out by the multitude of tasks ahead of me.\"", "Here are some suggestions on how to handle a large workload:\n\n- List your tasks and prioritize them\n- Think of which tasks add to the company's bottom line, and start there (Closest to the money!)\n- Exhale. Relax for a minute and collect yourself\n- Organize your tasks by which ones you can complete independently and which ones you need help with\n- Take sufficient breaks, so you do not exhaust yourself \n- Communicate your struggles with your leadership or team"]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "At Company ABC our success is greatly based on the engagement level of our employees. Do you consider yourself a reliable employee?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are ready to be a reliable and engaged team member. In which ways are you prepared to make an impact, if hired? How will you best show your appreciation for this position if Company ABC offers you the role?", "\"When you call my references you will see that I am a very reliable and willing worker. When hired by Company ABC, I plan to be a top performing employee right away. I'm excited about this opportunity!\"", "\"I do consider myself reliable. I have strong tenure in my previous work history, and I am always on time for work. You can be assured that if you hire me at Company ABC that you will not be disappointed in my dedication and performance.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "At Company ABC we are set apart from our competitors by our incredible customer service. What is your customer service philosophy?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to be sure that you are able and willing to carry the torch when it comes to stellar customer service. What does great customer service mean to you?", "\"My customer service philosophy is to always go above and beyond what the customer is expecting from you. When you pleasantly surprise them, they are sure to come back time and time again!\"", "\"My customer service philosophy is simple! I believe in always delivering the same level of customer service that I would expect as a customer. I am sure to be helpful, and motivated by kindness in all that I do.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "If you could choose to work in any department at Company ABC, which would you choose?", "answers": ["There are likely many different departments and areas that you could grow into with Company ABC. If you could choose any particular department to work in, which would you choose? Talk candidly to the interviewer about your desires for growth and opportunity within their organization.", "\"I have always leaned more towards positions within the fresh produce department. I am a great cook and am always interested in different fresh produce, trying dishes from different cultures, and encouraging my customers to do the same.\"", "\"In my grocery store experience, I have worked primarily with receiving stock and inventory, and have spent some time in the produce department as well. I am most comfortable in receiving and inventory; however, I am open to working in any department where you see fit.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "Do you have experience in handling monetary transactions?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are capable of handling cash and credit card transactions. Talk about your math skills, your reputation for being an honest employee, and also your excellent customer service skills.", "\"I have a couple of years' experience working as a cashier at a local grocery store. I am very good at making customers feel at ease while I ring them through. I have experience with a variety of Point of Sale systems as well as Moneris. My math skills are sharp, so you can be assured that I am always returning the correct amount of change!\"", "\"I have minimal experience in handling physical cash although I have been responsible for managing an eCommerce website. I understand the basics of cash in/cash out. I am strong in mathematics and can quickly calculate correct change, for instance.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "At Company ABC we like to train and promote our employees as often as possible. Where would you want to see your career with Company ABC take you?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you are looking forward to a bright future with Company ABC. If offered excellent training and the potential of internal promotions, would that excite you? Discuss with the interviewer your thoughts on the potential career path with Company ABC.", "\"I like that you promote from within and also that you train whenever possible. I would like to see my career take me to a store manager or human resources type of role with Company ABC. That possibility is fascinating to me!\"", "\"I would love to see myself growing into a more prominent leadership role within your organization. My career interests align very nicely with your company's goals which helps me to see a great long-term fit here.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "Describe an ongoing problem at your current or former employer that you were able to overcome.", "answers": ["Every place of employment will have its challenges. Talk to the interviewer about a specific issue that you were able to overcome in your previous role. Be sure to remain positive. Avoid complaining or saying negative things about your last employer or co-workers.", "\"In my most recent position we had an ongoing concern with our most popular stock depleting before the new shipment would come in. Customers would become annoyed and upset, which then became an issue for me as the Customer Service Manager. I decided to document the cycle and then approach the Inventory Manager about my concern. We were able to work on a solution for ordering from that particular supplier. In the end, this solved the majority of supply issues.\"", "\"In my most recent positions, communication was our biggest problem.  I implemented, with the support of management, a weekly email update that kept our departments talking to each other instead of pointing fingers when an issue would arise.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "Do you prefer doing work on a routine day-to-day basis or do you prefer mixing up your routine occasionally?", "answers": ["Are you the individual who prefers to know what the routine will be, or do you thrive on the challenge and excitement of unpredictability?", "\"I prefer working in a more predictable environment because I can be more effective in my tasks. With that said, I can certainly work in an unpredictable environment from time to time.\"", "\"Currently, I work around a random routine. Part of this is due to the nature of my role, and part of it is due to communication issues between departments. I can work in either type of environment; however, I certainly do prefer an organized workplace.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "Tell me about a time when you disagreed with your boss.", "answers": ["Even though you may have a great relationship with your employer, there may be times where you don't see eye to eye. Think of a conflict or disagreement you had with your boss where you responded well, either by suggesting a compromise or taking a calm, relaxed stance when you could have responded in a heated tone. Compromise puts you in a great position with your boss, because it shows your desire to work together and highlights your creative problem-solving abilities.", "\"I had a boss that regularly forced overtime on employees at the last minute with no opportunity to make childcare arrangements or plan changes.  Sometimes he knew about the need for plenty of time to warn everyone but did not.  I spoke with him at length about morale, and eventually, he started giving the notice sooner, making everyone's lives easier.\"", "\"I have done my best to always get along with my bosses, but inevitably I've disagreed with some of them in the past. Generally, the disagreements have been surrounding distribution of tasks among the staff. When I see that employees are unfairly treated, it bothers me. I'm not very confrontational, but I did pull my boss aside on a few occasions to let her know that the treatment seemed unfair and it was hurting morale. She was not thrilled at first since it questioned her authority and knowledge of the team, but after explaining how it was impacting the morale and productivity, she understood.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "What is the worst thing a previous manager could say about you?", "answers": ["Think about some mistakes you have made at work. How did you handle them? If a manager were to give you feedback or criticism, what might they say? Use an example that shows you are the type of person who is looking to improve and grow. You may have gotten some harsh criticism in the past, but you know how to be constructive and improve from it.", "\"When I started at my last job I had a pretty big learning curve. The software and my daily tasks were all very new to me. I made a lot of mistakes in the beginning because I felt rushed and wanted to learn as quickly as I could. My manager told me to slow down and not worry so much about keeping up with the people who have been there for a while. He was understanding, and it helped to learn that it's okay to take my time so that I can notice the details and avoid mistakes.\"", "\"I have received constructive feedback in regards to my patience level when it comes to my own mistakes. I have been working on allowing myself to make errors and quickly recover from them.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "When have you worked amongst a diverse group of people?", "answers": ["Are you accustomed to working with a very large or diverse team of individuals? Assure the interviewer that you can handle an environment that offers diversity.", "\"I have worked with diverse groups of people most of my career, including my time in University. I am most comfortable, and happy, in this type of environment because it offers a great learning opportunity.\"", "\"I can work cordially with all types of individuals, and I appreciate and encourage diversity in the workplace.  Most of the positions I have been in have offered a great deal of diversity.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "How do you deal with stressful situations?", "answers": ["Ah, the challenge of stress management! Your ability to manage stress will directly influence your ability to do your job successfully, assisting others on the team and providing support for clients or customers. Before answering this question, think of some ways you have learned to deal with stress at work. Sometimes you can't take a break when you need it, so what will you do?\n\nF\"I've learned some helpful breathing techniques that I can do while I'm at work. Even when I'm feeling rushed or overwhelmed by a patient situation, I can slow down my breath and remain calm. Patient care will always be my top priority, and that's why I've learned to manage my stress effectively.\"", "\"I've learned some helpful breathing techniques that I can do while I'm at work. Even when I'm feeling rushed or overwhelmed by a patient situation, I can slow down my breath and remain calm. Patient care will always be my top priority, and that's why I've learned to manage my stress effectively.\"", "\"Stress is part of any demanding job, and I embrace it to the fullest.  I take good care of myself and prioritize my workload to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "What questions do you have for me, about Company ABC?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to have questions ready for the interviewer. Review the company website and other online resources to ensure the questions you are asking are not mundane, or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a list of items you could have found the answers to from merely watching a video on their company site! \n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What is your favorite part about working here? \n- What is the company's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the most significant change in the grocery industry over the past three years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"Thank you for asking - I do have a few questions. What is top of mind when it comes to filling this role? Also, what types of career growth opportunities would follow this position? And lastly, do you have internal candidates who are also interviewing for this position?\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "What are you looking for in a job?", "answers": ["This can be a tricky question to answer if you've never had a job before! Think about your education and any volunteer experience you have received or training. What are some aspects of those experience that you enjoyed? For many people, working in an environment that is positive helps them to feel more motivated and often more productive. Your coworkers can have a huge influence on your experience as well. If you work with positive and encouraging people, you will feel appreciated and cared for at work. Review the job description so that you can also share some of what you're looking forward to learning. The most exciting part of a new job is that you have so much room to grow and learn. This is the beginning of your career so get excited!", "\"I am new to my career so I am looking for a job that will give me great training and a positive work environment.\"", "\"I'm looking for a company with which I can grow, and a team that will help me do it. I want to make the right decision with my first job out of school that will put me on the right career path.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "What is your current salary?", "answers": ["A potential employer will often base their offer on your current salary. You should be transparent about your most recent earnings and be prepared to back up any salary requests.", "\"I am currently earning a base salary of $28,000. I am looking for a competitive salary in my next position.\"", "\"I am currently making $50,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "Do you prefer to work in a team based position or individually?", "answers": ["In which situation are you the happiest and most productive? Talk to the interviewer about your preference when it comes to teamwork or working individually. Be sure to avoid pigeonholing yourself into one particular scenario (IE: I only like to work by myself).", "\"I have found, in the past, that I work best in an individually driven environment; however, I can certainly be productive in a team-based setting as well.\"", "\"I am a fan of team-based positions where everyone has something unique to offer. It creates a great diversity and generates ideas that may not have occurred in an individual based work environment.\""]}, {"topic": "Grocery+Store", "question": "How do you motivate your fellow team members?", "answers": ["You don't have to be a manager or a team leader to motivate others. Offering a listening ear or providing words of encouragement can make a world of difference to your coworkers. Sometimes, just being a positive influence and showing up consistently can also make a difference. \n\nIf you have worked in a leadership role, think of ways you helped set clear goals or helped individuals cultivate a new skill. Reflect on your experience and share some ideas that you have helped encourage others to keep up the good work!", "\"I motivate my fellow team members by coming to work with an exceptional attitude every day. I won't allow anyone's bad mood to let me down. That influence alone has helped many of my coworkers get through their day on a more positive note.\"", "\"I motivate others by complimenting their work, asking them their opinion, and making them feel like a valued part of the team.\""]}]